82 Plymouth Avenue, Maplewood, NJ 07040 • mark@alienresident.net • 347 228 3696

# Summary

I am a User Experience Designer with over fifteen years in interactive media. My career spans the breadth of digital production, from production art to web design and front-end development. As a User Experience Designer, my in depth understanding of the design process allows me to meet user goals while balancing aesthetics and technical constraints.

## **UX/UI Skills**

- · Usability Testing, User Interviews, and Personas
- · Sketching, Storyboarding, and Paper Prototyping
- · Wireframing, Card Sorting, and High-fidelity Prototyping
- · Markup (HTML) and Styling (CSS)
- · Visual Design, Style Guides, and Style Tiles
- · Typography and Graphic Production

## Technical Skills

- Photoshop, OmniGraffle, Illustrator, Flash, Fireworks
- HTML, CSS, Sass & Compass, Javascript & jQuery
- . SVN & Git, PHP, MySQL, Drupal

# **Professional Experience**

## **New York University**

October 2008-present

#### **User Experience Specialist**

Digital Communications Group, Information Technology Services August 2014–present

- Create a new responsive user interface for Sakai, an Open Source Learning Management System
- · Commit back the user experience work from NYU Classes to Sakai
- Design a new user interface for NYU's Email Direct a bulk email communication tool for NYU administrators

#### **User Experience Designer**

Academic Technology Services, Information Technology Services October 2011-August 2014

- Design a new user interface for NYU Classes the Learning Management System (LMS) based on extensive usability testing
- Create a 'Mobile First' prototype for our redesign of <u>MediaCommons</u> a
  digital network for professors and post-graduate students of film and media
  studies

#### Interactive Designer and Developer

Faculty Technology Services, Information Technology Services
October 2008–October 2011

- Design and develop <u>MediaCommons</u> a digital network for professors and post-graduate students — using Drupal
- Establish a distinctive look and feel for the *MediaCommons* network and it's project sites
- Design and develop book and photo viewing websites, and streaming audio and video for the NYU Libraries' special digital collections

## Columbia University

August 2001-September 2008

#### Senior Web Designer and Developer

Columbia University Digital Knowledge Ventures (a small 'digital agency' within Columbia University)

May 2005-September 2008

- Create educational course content and departmental websites for Columbia University and affiliated non-profits
- Design and develop websites using open source content management systems and static html

#### Web Designer and Developer

Columbia University Digital Knowledge Ventures August 2001–May 2005

- Work with Columbia Faculty to design and develop interactive e-seminars and courses
- Design and develop interactive maps, audio slideshows, podcasts, and basic video production and post-production for streaming video and DVD

# European Graduate School

Fall 1999-Summer 2008

#### **Assistant Director for Web Design and Development**

Dept. of Media and Communications

- Establish a visual identity for a new university and a strong online presence
- · Design, develop, and maintain the European Graduate School's website

## Scholastic

January 2000-May 2001

#### Web Designer

e-Scholastic

- Design educational, commercial, and promotional websites for Scholastic
- Design daily site graphics, flash based interactive quizzes and educational activities

## Thirteen, WNET

February 1998-Decemeber 1999

#### **Production Artist and Animator**

Heritage Project DVD-ROM

 Produce over 500 interactive maps for an DVD-ROM historical atlas feature of the award winning Jewish history television series, "The Heritage Project"

1991-1994 B.A. History and Philosophy, University College Dublin, Ireland

# Education

1999–2007 **Ph.D. Media & Communication**, *European Graduate School*, Saas-Fee, Switzerland 1998–2001 **Certificate in Film Production**, *The New School*, New York, NY 1995–1996 **M.Phil. Medieval History**, *Trinity College*, *Dublin University*, Ireland

## Additional Information

## **Teaching**

**The New School**, Fall 2004–Spring 2008 Adjunct faculty member, *Media Studies* 

· Courses: Foundations of Media Design and Digital Video Effects

**Columbia University**, Summer 2005–Summer 2008 Instructor, *High School Program* 

· Course: Digital Filmmaking

## Organizations

- Co-Founder: NYU UX Group & NYU Web Designers and Developers Group
- Co-Organizer: DrupalCamp NYC 9 & 10 NYC Drupal Users Group
- **Member**: IxDA NYC UXPA Gotham Sass Meetup NYC Drupal Users Group Agile Experience Design Meetup Type Directors Club

# Selected Presentations, Event Organization, and Trainings

#### **Presentations**

- MediaCommons 2.0 at Digital Library Federation Forum 5th May, 2009
- Fixing Broken User Experience NYU ITS All Hands Meeting 21st September, 2012
- Rapid Protoyping Techniques TorchTech: UX Networking Breakfast 23rd April, 2014
- Sakai: Meet MORPHEUS at Open Apereo 2014 2nd June, 2014
- Beyond Putting Lipstick on the Pig at EdUI 2014 30th September, 2014

## **Event Organization**

- **DrupalCamp NYC 9 & 10** Co-Organizer & Designer *NYC Drupal Users Group* June & December 2011
- Usability @ NYU Co-Organizer NYU UX group 11th December, 2012
- UX @ NYU Co-Organizer NYU UX group 14th November, 2013
- UX Networking Breakfast Co-Organizer TorchTech & NYU UX group 23rd April, 2014

## **Trainings**

- Mobile Prototyping Essentials with Rachel Hinman, Interaction 12 February 2012
- Sketching Interfaces with Jason Mesut & Sam Smith, Interaction 12 February 2012
- Do It Yourself Usability Testing with Steve Krug, Rosenfeld Media May 2012
- UX Leadership with Kim Goodwin, Rosenfeld Media October 2012
- Scaling User Interfaces with Amy Schade, Nielsen Norman Group August 2014